<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<cheatsheet title="Circle/Ellipse fitting tool">

	<intro>
		<description>
		    This cheat sheet helps you to open an image, and shows you how to use the circle/ellipse
		    fitting tool with the file. If you have just completed the previous cheat sheet, please
		    close all your data file parts.
	    </description>
	</intro>

   <item title="Data Browsing Perspective">
      <description>
         Please choose the data browsing perspective if you do not already have it selected (nothing
         will happen if you do not).
      </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective(org.eclipse.ui.perspectives.showPerspective.perspectiveId=org.edna.workbench.application.perspective.DataPerspective)"/>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Open File">
      <description>
         Click to open an example file from the &apos;data&apos; project containing a test image.
      </description>
      <command
            required="false"
            serialization="org.eclipse.ui.navigate.openResource(filePath=data/examples/results/billeA_4201_EF_XRD_5998.edf)"/>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Select 'Circle/Ellipse Fitting' tool">
      <description>
         Select the 'Circle/Ellipse Fitting' tool from the toolbar above the plot, tools labelled 'Image
         tools used to profile and inspect images'. These tools may be obscured on Linux if the
         window containing the plot is too small.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Circle-only fitting">
      <description>
         A button near the top left of the tool view can be toggled on to restrict the shape
         fitted to a circle instead of an ellipse. It affects the current fit and any future fits.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Fit a circle or an ellipse">
      <description>
         Select an elliptical or circular feature in the image to fit. Click on at least 3 (or 5
         for an ellipse) points of the selected feature spreading points over broad curves and
         concentrating points on tighter sections. A dashed segmented line is shown that joins the
         selected points together. After the third point is clicked, the fitted circle is shown and
         more points can be added. To finish adding points, click on the last point again without
         moving the mouse. If the circle-only button is off, then the fitted shape becomes an ellipse
         on the fifth point added, otherwise it remains a circle.
         <p>The fitted ellipse is displayed with handle boxes on the clicked points and a centre
         handle box shown on its major axis.</p>
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Fitted ellipse parameters">
      <description>
         Look at the 'Circle/Ellipse Fitting' tool view on the right hand side of the image. Here you will
         see a table of geometric parameters of the fitted ellipses. The columns include major and
         minor semi-axes lengths (equivalent to radius of a circle), angle of the major axis and
         centre coordinates. For a circular fit, the semi-axes are equal in length and the angle is
         zero.
      </description>
   </item>
   <item
         title="Adjusting a fitted ellipse">
      <description>
         Any of the handles can be clicked and dragged to adjust its position and influence the
         fitting of the ellipse. The centre handle solely translates the whole ellipse and its
         points.
      </description>
      <onCompletion>
         Congratulations, you can now fit circles and ellipses to features in images. Try with your own images.
      </onCompletion>
   </item>

       	
</cheatsheet>
